# VENKAT RAMSHESH (LinkedIn)

### **WORK HISTORY**

#### Field Engineer, 05/2022 - present United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS)

- Installation and support for laptops, workstations, printers, and AV equipment of USCIS staff, students, classroom, and offices ensuring minimal downtime
- System software updates, hardware and vulnerability fixes, imaging of computers, maintenance of system servers and switches, UPS, VPN/remote worker support, PowerShell for active directory reports
- Learnt Python, HTML/CSS (front-end), and Flask (back-end) programming (Code for few projects: <a href="https://github.com/kris1878/pythonprojects">https://github.com/kris1878/pythonprojects</a>). Used libraries like Flask, Requests, Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, Boto3, Turicreate for these projects.
- Machine Learning Specialization from the University of Washington/Coursera. Used python and turicreate to implement machine learning models for regression, classification, and decision tree
- Certified in AWS Solutions Architect Associate, Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS Serverless learning badge and COMPTIA+. Written technology-based blogs and implemented projects for:

Networking: VPC, Subnets, NAT, IGW, Egress gateway, Jump box Highly available and scalable architecture: Conference raffle webpage using CloudFormation, Application Load Balancers

**Instances**: Blog page on EC2 instance (<a href="http://44.207.232.191:8000/">http://44.207.232.191:8000/</a>), RDS instances for database

**Serverless**: API's, Lambda function, Dynamo DB tables, SNS, SAM, transcribing

**Storage**: S3 for static website (<a href="https://vramsheshpersonalblog.com">https://vramsheshpersonalblog.com</a>), EFS, EBS Security/Delivery: Encryption, SSL certificates for website, Presigned URL, VPN, CDN, IAM, Organizations, Cognito

**Automation/Devops**: CI/CD, Jenkins, Ansible, Elastic beanstalk for raffle webpage, GitHub automation for personal webpage, CloudFormation

#### Field Engineer II, 11/2020 - 05/2021 Cytek Biosciences

- Installation and support for Aurora flow cytometer in Philadelphia/NJ area in a timely manner
- Regular system preventative and update visits
- Identified major system issues that could arise and provided solutions

## Field Engineer II, 01/2015 - 11/2020 GE Healthcare Lifesciences/Cytiva

- Installation and support for GE OMX super resolution (OMX V3, V4, SR and SR plus models) and Delta Vision microscopes in North America, Asia, and Europe
- Troubleshooting and fixing system issues on-site and remotely
- Yearly PM and hardware/software updates, customer training

### Research Instructor/Facility Manager, 12/2007 - 12/2014 Medical University of South Carolina

- Provide bioengineering and managerial support for the successful day to day working of the Advanced Imaging Core that included eight confocal, multiphoton & fluorescence microscopes and image processing workstations
- Instructed users on microscopy/imaging usage and projects, consulted on projects involving use of light microscopy techniques within and outside the university
- Organizer and instructor for the Charleston Light Microscopy Workshop for the Biosciences (2008-2014)

- 267-858-8955
- venkatramshesh@yahoo.com
- vramsheshpersonalblog.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated, collaborative biomedical engineer skilled in IT, cloud, python programming, Machine Learning, security, and devops. Effective engineer offering excellent skills in technology, research, installation, training, and testing of systems. Forward-thinking, problem-solving professional offering years of experience working in fast-paced environments.

### **PROGRAMMING SKILLS**

Python, Matlab, C, Image J, HTML/CSS Versed in Windows and Linux OS

#### **EDUCATION**

**Ph.D.**, Biomedical Engineering, 2008 University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill

**M.S**, Biomedical Engineering, 2002 University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill

**B.E**, Instrumentation Engineering, 1999 Mumbai University - Mumbai

# PROFFESIONAL ACTIVITIES

• AWS Community Builder

# EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Member of UNC squash team
- Recreational salsa dancer